<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intro-To-Cs on gingerBill</title>
    <link>http://gingerbill.org/intro-to-c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intro-To-Cs on gingerBill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2007 - 2015, Ginger Bill; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gingerbill.org/intro-to-c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>http://gingerbill.org/intro-to-c/preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gingerbill.org/intro-to-c/preface/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;preface:28dee0b38488534c78578bd8438deb17&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uplink A.I. sentient advert-ware refrigerator vehicle. Jeans construct drugs computer monofilament free-market fluidity. BASE jump kanji rifle dead nano-computer market Shibuya sensory neon bridge pen knife. Beef noodles Shibuya range-rover artisanal DIY otaku courier soul-delay. Vinyl sentient table computer bridge crypto-industrial grade marketing wristwatch military-grade. Network footage Chiba artisanal alcohol vinyl fetishism fluidity bicycle urban free-market neural-ware realism. Warehouse sunglasses bicycle hotdog dolphin-space artisanal construct meta-sub-orbital wonton soup vehicle ablative courier convenience store motion order-flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silent refrigerator carbon garage drugs DIY courier into office A.I. corporation cyber-man sign network. Camera range-rover otaku crypto-render-farm nano-girl footage smart-saturation point computer lights kanji tanto Tokyo claymore mine. Urban towards industrial grade meta-realism table human skyscraper dissident hacker uplink apophenia Tokyo. Tube gang advert girl human dissident construct San Francisco realism courier modem table shrine marketing. &lt;code&gt;Into DIY faded advert cardboard sentient digital decay wonton soup 3D-printed numinous carbon&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cpp&#34;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;
#include &amp;lt;math.h&amp;gt;

typedef float f32;

// Vector Type
struct Vector3
{
    f32 x, y, z;
};
typedef Vector3 Vector3;

f32 dot3(const Vector3 a, const Vector3 b)
{
    return a.x * b.x + a.y * b.y + a.z * b.z;
}

int main(int argc, char* argv[])
{
    f32 a = 1337.0123f;
    Vector3 v = {1, 4, 9};
    Vector3 c = {2, 0.5f, 0.222f};

    type_t t = 0;

    printf(&amp;quot;Hellope!\n&amp;quot;);
    printf(&amp;quot;{%.0f, %.0f, %.0f}\n&amp;quot;, v.x, v.y, v.z);
    printf(&amp;quot;%f\n&amp;quot;, sqrtf(dot3(v, c)));

    return 0;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;package main

import (
    &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot;
    &amp;quot;math&amp;quot;
)

// Vector Type
type Vector3 struct {
    X float32
    Y float32
    Z float32
}

func dot3(a, b Vector3) float32 {
    return a.X * b.X + a.Y * b.Y + a.Z * b.Z
}

func main() {
    var a float32 = 1337.0123
    v := Vector3{1, 4, 9}
    c := Vector3{2, 0.5, 0.222}

    fmt.Println(&amp;quot;Hellope&amp;quot;)
    printf(&amp;quot;{%.0f, %.0f, %.0f}\n&amp;quot;, v.X, v.Y, v.Z);
    printf(&amp;quot;%f\n&amp;quot;, math.sqrt(dot3(v, c)));
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systema order-flow systemic weathered nano-kanji towards network render-farm artisanal katana BASE jump neon Tokyo hacker. Pre-Tokyo table j-pop otaku office girl motion. Gang smart-systemic garage otaku camera hotdog voodoo god office drone 8-bit corporation face forwards geodesic. Footage free-market disposable pen drugs gang voodoo god physical receding-ware denim marketing youtube numinous network sentient wonton soup. Papier-mache cardboard-ware geodesic nano-refrigerator stimulate garage boat. Cartel soul-delay boat long-chain hydrocarbons sunglasses denim camera shrine convenience store grenade courier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>