<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on gingerBill</title>
    <link>/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on gingerBill</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Error States</title>
      <link>/show/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/show/2/</guid>
      <description>Notes:  Exceptions — And Why Odin Will Never Have Them Essential vs Accidental Properties Exception handling I used the term structured exception handling which is different to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s SEH, I meant structured in the structured programming sense  Structured Exception Handling Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s SEH   Error handling and Go Odin is a multi-valued type system, compared to most languages which have singularly-valued type systems.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools of Thought</title>
      <link>/show/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/show/1/</guid>
      <description>Notes: Schools  Procedural/Pragmatist Mathematical/Functional Bodging Business/Managerial  Definitions  Bodge  (British Slang) A quick and dirty job, something done very hastily. Make it look good for the next day or two and if it falls down after that, it&amp;rsquo;s alright. https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=bodge    Books and References  A Conflict of Visions - Thomas Sowell Fallen human nature Rousseau&amp;rsquo;s theory of human nature  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Flaw of Ownership Semantics</title>
      <link>/article/2020/06/21/the-ownership-semantics-flaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/06/21/the-ownership-semantics-flaw/</guid>
      <description>I have been toying with a theoretical idea for the past 18 months off-and-on in my head and I have not fully articulated it aloud yet. It is regarding the concept of Ownership Semantics (OS) or Move Semantics in programming languages. Fundamentally this article is a criticism of the concept and states that the concept is a duality of traditional OOP but applied to a different area.
General Definitions of Terminology A general list of definitions of terminology used within this article in order to minimize confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash Fads Model (Audio Article)</title>
      <link>/article/2020/06/13/flash-fads-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/06/13/flash-fads-model/</guid>
      <description>Audio Article:
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
