<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>c on gingerBill</title>
    <link>/tags/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in c on gingerBill</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering Alembic</title>
      <link>/article/2022/07/11/reverse-engineering-alembic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2022/07/11/reverse-engineering-alembic/</guid>
      <description>For my work at JangaFX, we require the use of the Alembic interchange file format. We have been using other libraries which wrap reading the Alembic file format but because it is not the native library, it has numerous issues due to the generic interface.
I spent nearly 4 days trying to get the official Alembic C++ API, https://github.com/alembic/alembic/, to compile correctly and then use the API itself. Numerous times the compilation would get corrupted (it compiled but none of the tests even ran) and when I got it work (on another machine), the API itself was a labyrinth to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value Propagation Experiment Part 2</title>
      <link>/article/2021/09/06/value-propagation-experiment-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2021/09/06/value-propagation-experiment-part-2/</guid>
      <description>**[Originally from a Twitter Thread]**
I have revisited The Value Propagation Experiment and have come to a different conclusion as to why it failed and how I recovered it.
The recovery work has been merged into master now with this PR: https://github.com/odin-lang/Odin/pull/1082
I think there were three things which were confusing which make it look like a failure of an experiment:
 try was a confusing name for what the semantics were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value Propagation Experiment</title>
      <link>/article/2021/07/05/value-propagation-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2021/07/05/value-propagation-experiment/</guid>
      <description>[Originally from a Twitter Thread]
Part 2 of this Experiment
The Idea I recently experimented with adding a feature into Odin which allowed for a way to propagate a value by early returning if that value was false or not nil. It was in a similar vein to Rust&amp;rsquo;s try! which became ?, or Zig&amp;rsquo;s try, etc.
I have now removed it from Odin. But why?
The Problem The hypothesis was that that this idiom was common:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untyped Types</title>
      <link>/article/2021/03/07/untyped-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2021/03/07/untyped-types/</guid>
      <description>When I was designing the constant value system in Odin, I wanted literals (especially numbers) to &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo;. I was inspired by how both Ada1 and Go2 both handled their constant value systems. But this lead me to a realization that there are two general different models of thought when it comes to values in programming languages.
 Model-1: Expressions have a type, not all expressions may have a value. Therefore all values must have a type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relative Pointers</title>
      <link>/article/2020/05/17/relative-pointers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/05/17/relative-pointers/</guid>
      <description>Absolute Pointers Pointers are a value type in programming languages that store a memory address. A pointer references a location in memory, and obtaining the value stored at this location in memory is known as dereferencing a pointer. Pointers are part and parcel of using languages like C, and are an extremely powerful tool. Pointers can be treated as a form of reference type, a value that refers to another typed value in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reply to _Let&#39;s stop copying C_</title>
      <link>/article/2020/01/25/a-reply-to-lets-stop-copying-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/01/25/a-reply-to-lets-stop-copying-c/</guid>
      <description>I read the article Let&amp;rsquo;s stop copying C about 3 years ago. Recently someone brought it up again and I thought I would comment on the points being made. The article argues that newer languages ought not to copy the mistakes of C and comment on may of C&amp;rsquo;s mistakes.
I recommend reading the original article first before reading this one as I will be commenting directly on the subsections of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
