<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychology on gingerBill</title>
    <link>/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psychology on gingerBill</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence of Programming</title>
      <link>/article/2021/02/01/the-essence-of-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2021/02/01/the-essence-of-programming/</guid>
      <description>One thing I have noticed a lot when a programmer is struggling to solve a problem, especially a novice, is that he is stuck worrying about the &amp;ldquo;best way&amp;rdquo; to implement the solution rather than actually understanding the problem he has. I believe a lot of this stems from not understanding the essence of what programming fundamentally is.
Essentially Ordered Aspects In a previous article of mine, I state that &amp;ldquo;Programming is a tool to solve problems that you have in the domain of computers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Flaw of Ownership Semantics</title>
      <link>/article/2020/06/21/the-ownership-semantics-flaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/06/21/the-ownership-semantics-flaw/</guid>
      <description>I have been toying with a theoretical idea for the past 18 months off-and-on in my head and I have not fully articulated it aloud yet. It is regarding the concept of Ownership Semantics (OS) or Move Semantics in programming languages. Fundamentally this article is a criticism of the concept and states that the concept is a duality of traditional OOP but applied to a different area.
General Definitions of Terminology A general list of definitions of terminology used within this article in order to minimize confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash Fads Model (Audio Article)</title>
      <link>/article/2020/06/13/flash-fads-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/2020/06/13/flash-fads-model/</guid>
      <description>Audio Article:
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
